翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
With the implementation of the removeLast complete,
随着 removeLast 的实现
we now have arrived at the mighty Alist.
我们已经得到了强大的 AList
Now, the Alist works beautifully.
AList 工作得非常漂亮
It'll be fast, wonderful.
它很快很棒
But it has one major limitation, which you can see here--
但有一个主要的限制，你可以在这里看到...
namely, that the list can never hold more than 100 items.
链表中的项永远不能超过100个
So in other words, once the concrete reality has reached this point, where size is 100,
换句话说，一旦真实情况到了这个点，size 达到了100
and thus we consider all items in the array used,
我们认为数组中的所有项都被使用了
we know, of course, that the invariant says that 100 is the place where the next item's going to get inserted.
不变量说100是下一项要被插入的地方
So what happens if we insert into the Alist above?
我们插入上面的链表会发生什么呢？
Well, we'll get an index out of bounds exception.
会得到一个索引超出界限的异常
And it'll say, sorry, can't put something in a position that doesn't exist.
它不能把东西放在不存在的位置
The next thing you might ponder is, what should we do about it?
那么我们应该做些什么呢？
So maybe think about that a moment.
思考一会
So the most obvious thing you might want is to make the array bigger.
可能最容易想到的就是使数组更大
Now, of course, in Java, that's not actually possible.
当然在 Java 中，这实际上是不可能的
So what should we do instead?
那么应该怎么做呢？
Well, one approach is what we'll call resizing arrays.
一种方法是调整数组大小
Now, of course, this name seems to directly contradict what I just said, which is that arrays in Java can't be resized.
这跟我刚才所说的，Java 中数组不能调整大小，似乎正相矛盾
So we're going to do something that seems like a little bit of a hack.
我们要做一些看起来有点像黑客的事情
So basically, what we're going to do is when the array gets too full--
基本上，当数组变得太满时...
in other words, when size equals items.length,
换句话说，当 size == items.length 时
when the abstract reality of the situation
当抽象的现实情况是...
is that the user expects as many items in the list as there are in the concrete list--
用户期望链表中的项与实际链表中的项一样多时
then we will do the following.
我们将执行以下操作
We will say int a equals new int size plus 1.
int[] a = new int[size+1]
So we'll make an array in this case that is 1 larger
在本例中，我们将创建多1个 size 的数组
because this has enough room to hold not just the information we already had, but also one additional item.
因为这里不仅有足够的空间容纳我们已经拥有的信息，还有一个额外的项
Geez, spam call.
垃圾电话
Go away.
走开
Next thing we'll do is we'll say System.arraycopy, yada, yada.
接下来要说的是 System.arraycopy(...)
I'm not going to show all the syntax.
我不会展示所有的语法
So all of this information gets copied from our array to this copy of the array.
所有这些信息都会从数组复制到数组的这个副本中
And a is just some variable that points to this array.
a 只是指向这个数组的某个变量
Currently, it has nothing at all to do with our Alist.
目前它跟我们的 AList 一点关系都没有
It's just a local variable.
这只是一个局部变量
Then we say a size equals 11.
a[size] = 11
And by that, I mean let's go to that last position
意思是让我们到最后一个位置
and put the number that we want to insert.
把想要插入的数字放进去
Then, and this is the really interesting part,
然后才是真正有趣的部分
we take the items memory box.
我们拿着 items 内存盒子
And we say, that old concrete list we had laying around here,
这里的老旧的链表
this concrete array-- we're done with it.
这个数组...我们受够了
It's no longer useful to-- it's too small for our purposes.
它没用了...对于我们的目的太小了
And instead, we're going to make the items memory box here point at this new array we just created.
取而代之，我们将这里的 items 内存盒指向刚刚创建的新数组
And that will be destroyed by the garbage collector.
垃圾收集器会把它销毁
And now we have an array that is large enough to hold all of our items.
现在我们有了一个足够大的数组来容纳所有项
So we call this process here in this little range
我们把这个小范围的过程...
where we create a new array and copy it resizing.
创建新数组并复制称为调整大小
Now, of course, we didn't actually resize anything at all.
实际上根本没有调整任何东西的大小
We created a copy and set our items pointer to our new array.
创建一个副本，将 items 指针指向新数组
But the effect is the same.
但效果是一样的
So we're going to implement this in a moment.
我们将在稍后实现这一点
I encourage you-- before I give it away in the next video,
我鼓励你们...在下一个视频中讲述之前
you can try it out on your own.
自己试一试
So if you click here on this link
点击这里的链接
or you go to LectureCode repo,
或者访问课程代码库
you'll get what we had before the naive implementation.
将得到之前幼稚实现中的所有东西
And so maybe try out doing this,
也许可以试试这样做
though you don't have to because you'll have to do this in project 1A,
虽然你不必这么做，因为在项目1A 中你必须这么做
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
anyway-- but your choice.
你自己决定